A Guide to the Walther F. Goebel papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA162
Rockefeller Archive Center
Walther F. Goebel papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1916-1976, bulk 1934-1960
bulk
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
Goebel, Walther Frederick
FA162
11.5 Cubic Feet
Biographical/Historical note
Dr. Goebel (1899-) a biochemist, dedicated his time and energy to the study of the body's chemical defense against infection by microorganisms. He joined the Rockefeller Institute as research assistant, 1924-1927, associate, 1927-1934, associate member, 1934-1944, member, 1944-1957, and professor, 1957-1970. He became professor emeritus of the Rockefeller University in 1970.
Professor Goebel received the Avery-Landsteiner Prize of the European Society of Immunologists, in 1973 and honorary doctor of science degrees from Middleburry College, Vermont, in 1959 and the Rockefeller University, in 1978.
Goebel was born on December 24, 1899 in Palo Alto, California. He received a Ph.D. degree from the University of Illinois in 1923 and served there as a scholar in Chemistry from 1920-1921.
Scope and Contents note
Walter Frederick Goebel papers consist of laboratory notebooks, seminars, printed materials, reprints, and minutes of meeting.
Arrangement note
Boxes (12-23) arranged chronologically within subject.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 G55
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
Biology -- Research; Biochemistry; Medicine, Preventive; Immunology; Chemistry; Medical sciences; Medical research; Medical education; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Rockefeller University; Goebel, Walther Frederick
- Bibliographies (Box 1)
- Biographical material (Box 1)
- Honors - Avery-Landsteiner Prize, 1973; 2 folders (Box 1)
- Photographs of W.F. Goebel; family; property, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - W.F. Goebel family, Date?
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes: mother, father, brother and 2 sisters.
  - 2 photographs of country property (?). [Above 2 items found with M.A. thesis], Date?
  - RI Hospital staff photograph. Identified, 1927 May 27
  - World's Fair, Philadelphia, Pa. of W.F. Goebel, sisters and father, 1926
  - Official portrait of W.F. Goebel by Louis Schmidt, 1927
  - W.F. Goebel's wife Cornelia in St. Thomas, Virgin Islands, 1932
  - Dr. and Mrs. W.F. Goebel. Passport photo, 1936 April 14
  - W.F. Goebel, 1938
  - W.F. Goebel print and negatives. Passport photo, 1940 October 3
  - W.F. Goebel, 1940
  - RI Hospital staff photograph. Identified, 1943
  - Abbaye Royaumont, France taken by W.F. Goebel attending meeting, 1952
  - W.F. Goebel official portrait, 1958 May 15
  - Informal laboratory photographs of W.F. Goebel, 1965
    Includes: W.F. Goebel w/dachshunds; w/instrument in laboratory; and proof print sheet.
  - W.F. Goebel by Colk. Portrait prints, 1970-1971
  - Informal lab photo of W.F. Goebel by Ingbet, 1973
  - Informal with dachshunds; without dogs, 1973
    [See #119 in Goebel bibliography - this photo of W.F. Goebel alone is used]
  - Dr. Goebel's dacshunds Sieglind and Isolde, Date?
  - Dr. Jesaitis, Dr. Reznikoff and W.F. Goebel at RU, 1973
  - Photographs of Dr. Goebel's home in Murray Bay, Canada on Christmas greetings cards by Dr. and Mrs. W.F. Goebel, Unknown
- Photographs of others (Box 1)
  - Oswald T. Avery at Colgate University. Group photograph of Colgate college band, 1900
  - In Avery laboratory photographs by W.F. Goebtel of Kenneth Goodner and René J. Dubos, circa 1932
  - Oswald T. Avery. Photograph by W.F. Goebel, circa 1945
  - Rufus Cole, circa 1950
  - Simon Flexner. Signed portrait, Date?
  - Karl Landsteiner in laboratory at RI. Photograph By W.F. Goebel, circa 1934
  - Peter K. Olitsky, Date?; Multiple prints
  - Thomas M. Rivers. Photograph by W.F. Goebel, circa 1940
    Includes handwritten inscription to W.F. Goebel
  - H.H. Taylor. In color, Date?
  - Otto Westphal with inscription to W.F. Goebel, 1970 November
- Scientific photographs/negatives (Box 1)
  - "Bacteriophage T7", 8x10 prints
  - Negatives/prints of figures for W.F. Goebel, "The nature of colicin K of Escherichia coli K235" PNAS 70 (1973) 854-858). (#118 in Goebel Bibliography)
  - Richard Willstaetter with inscription to W.F. Goebel, 1929
- Negatives (Box 1)
  - Turbidimeter (instrument), 1945 May 10; 36184 (Box 1)
    General
    8x10
  - Diploma given to volunteers for Immunization for dysentary-facillary at RI hospital during the war, 1943 May 20; 35072; 8x10 (Box 1)
- W.F. Goebel laboratory interiors in Smith Hall, 2nd floor, 1947 1949 1962 (Box 1)
  [See p. 5-15 for alphabetical listing (partial) of correspondence]
- Correspondence files, 5" Letter
  Scope and Contents
  Alphabetical File listing of the contents of Boxes 2-6.
  A complete Alphabetical listing of the individual correspondent names appears in the next section of this finding aid.
  Arrangement
  Alphabetically arranged.
  - Amano, Tsunehisa, 1956-1974 (Box 2)
  - Anderson, E.S., 1952-1970 (Box 2)
  - Ab-Ay (Box 2)
  - Brink, Frank Jr., 1958-1969 (Box 2)
  - Bronk, D.W., 1957-1972 (Box 2)
  - Ba (Box 2)
  - Be (Box 2)
  - Bi-Bro (Box 2)
  - Bro-Bu (Box 2)
  - Cole, Rufus [re] (Box 2)
  - C (Box 2)
  - Da-Del (Box 2)
  - Dem-Du (Box 3)
  - E (Box 3)
  - Flinn, Waldo R., 1955-1974 (Box 3)
  - Fredericq, Pierre, 1952-1972 (Box 3)
  - Fa-Fl (Box 3)
  - Fo-Fu (Box 3)
  - Ga-Gi (Box 3)
  - Gl-Go (Box 3)
  - Gr-Gy (Box 3)
  - Hugli, T.E., 1971-1973 (Box 3)
  - Hutton, John H., 1959-1963 (Box 3)
  - Ha (Box 3)
  - He (Box 3)
  - Hi (Box 3)
  - Hn-Hu (Box 4)
  - I (Box 4)
  - J (Box 4)
  - Ka-Ke (Box 4)
  - Ki-Ku (Box 4)
  - Lüderitz, Otto, 1958-1969 (Box 4)
  - Luria, S.E., 1945-1964 (Box 4)
  - Lwoff, A., 1952-1955 (Box 4)
  - La (Box 4)
  - Le (Box 4)
  - Li-Ly (Box 4)
  - Matsushita, Hiroshi, 1958-1962 (Box 4)
  - Morgan, Walter T.J., 1936-1973 (Box 4)
  - Mc (Box 4)
  - Ma (Box 5)
  - Me-Mi (Box 5)
  - Mo-Mu (Box 5)
  - Neter, Erwin F., 1964-1969 (Box 5)
  - Northrop, John H., 1950-1951 1952-1954 1958-1970 (Box 5)
  - Nowotny, Alois H., 1963-1969 (Box 5)
  - Na-Nu (Box 5)
  - Oxford University Press ca, 1942-1962 (Box 5)
  - O (Box 5)
  - Pa (Box 5)
  - Pe-Ph (Box 5)
  - Pi-Pu (Box 5)
  - Rank, Rüdiger, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Rüde, Erwin, 1960-1973 (Box 5)
  - Ra-Re (Box 5)
  - Ri (Box 5)
  - Ro-Ry (Box 6)
  - Seitz, Frederick, 1969-1977 (Box 6)
  - Staub, Anne Marie, 1952-1972 (Box 6)
  - Sa-Sch (Box 6)
  - Sci-Sh (Box 6)
  - Si-So (Box 6)
  - Sp-Sq (Box 6)
  - St-Sw (Box 6)
  - T, 1945-1964 (Box 6)
  - T, 1965-1974 (Box 6)
  - U, 1935-1970 (Box 6)
  - V, 1947-1975 (Box 6)
  - Westphal, Otto and Olga: Goebel/Westphal, 1956-1974; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Westphal/Goebel, 1955-1974; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Westphal biography/bibliography (Box 7)
  - Wilstätter, R., 1925 1936 (Box 7)
  - W, 1957-1963 (Box 7)
  - W, 1964-1974 (Box 7)
  - Y, 1951-1967 (Box 7)
  - Z, 1957-1971 (Box 7)
  - Unidentified (Box 7)
- Correspondence files, 5" Letter
  Alphabetical listing of correspondent names describing the materials in Boxes 2-6.
  - Amano, Tsunehisa, 1956-1974 (Box 2)
  - Anderson, E.S., 1952-1970 (Box 2)
  - Ab-Ay (Box 2)
    [NO ALPHAPHETICALLY]
  - Brink, Frank J., 1958-1969 (Box 2)
  - Bronk, Detlev W., 1957-1972 (Box 2)
  - Backhausz, Richard, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Backus, Robert C., 1962 (Box 2)
  - Bacolet Estate Guest House Ltd/Bacolet Inn, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - Baethke, Dorothy E., [re] Thea E. Fluevag, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Bacteriology, Journal of, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Baer, Albert M., 1973 (Box 2)
  - Bagdian, Genevieve, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Baitsholts, A.D., 1966 (Box 2)
  - Baker, Edgar E., 1956-1962 (Box 2)
  - Ballynahinch Castle, 1971 January 19 (Box 2)
    Includes 19 January 1971, Francis F. Storm Jr. /W.F. Goebel.
  - Balwani, T.L., 1967 (Box 2)
  - Barkman, Mrs. Bruce (W.F. Goebel daughter, Annie), 1963-1965 (Box 2)
  - Barkman, Bruce (son-in-law), 1963 1969 (Box 2)
  - Barry, Guy Thomas [re] Barsan, Iliana 1972-73, 1957-1968 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Baxter, A.G., 1962 (Box 2)
  - Bayless, Wm. A., 1969 (Box 2)
  - Beam, Alexander G., 1961-1962 (Box 2)
    Includes W.F. Goebel to Harvey Society Life Membership.
  - Beck, J.B. Mrs. (W.F. Goebel's sister), 1962-1963 (Box 2)
  - Beckmann Instruments, 1952-1960 (Box 2)
  - Beekman Tower Hotel, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Behan, John, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Behringwerke Aktiengesellschaft, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Bel Air Hotel, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Bell Telephone Laboratories [re] W.F. Goebel's Mercedes Benz, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Ben-Gurion, Renana, 1964 October 26-28 (Box 2)
    Includes invitation and preliminary program of 1964 October 26-28 Göttingen Symposium Bacteriocine und Bacteriocine Ähnliche Substanzen in Printed booklet.
  - Berkeley, Roger C.W., 1968 (Box 2)
  - Berkes, Daisy T., 1963 (Box 2)
  - Bernard, Paul, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Bernie, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Berry, George P. [re] John Hutton, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Beumer, Jacques, 1957-1973 (Box 2)
  - Biochemistry. Springer et al mss reviews, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Blaikie, Mrs. George (Blanche), 1967 (Box 2)
  - Blaikie, Johnson, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Blaisdell, Richard K., 1967 (Box 2)
    Includes 1967 photo of W.F. Goebel and others in Honolulu.
  - Blake, John B., 1966 (Box 2)
  - Blanc, Henri B. [re] vacation in Puerto Rico, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Blankenship. L. Vaughn, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Blatt, Sylvia [re] Lai-Yee Fung, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Bond, V.P. [re] D.D. Van Slyke 80 birthday celebration at Brookhaven National Laboratory Symposium, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Boots, Ralph [re] A. Dochez memorial service, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Bowen, George, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Boyd, William C., 1956-1961 (Box 2)
  - Brady, Roscoe O. [re] Chloe Tal, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Brandis, H., 1964-1965 (Box 2)
    Includes October 1964. Göttingen symposium program.
  - Brewer, George F., 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Bright, Mabel H., 1966 (Box 2)
  - Briles, Eve Mrs., 1974 (Box 2)
  - Broadbent, Margaret, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Bronson, Nathaniel (W.F. Goebel son-in-law), 1969 (Box 2)
  - Brooke, Marcus, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Brooker, Walter E. [re] German books to Middlebury College by W.F. and Julius Goebel, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Brossmer, Reinhard, 1958-1973 (Box 2)
  - Brown Co., 1961 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Austin, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Brown, George B., 1964 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Harrison (NAS) [re] Goebel (NAS member) concerns with International Scientific Affairs. Includes Goebel handwritten checklist, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Bryson, Vernon, 1956 (Box 2)
    Includes Fricke, Schwan, Li and V. Bryson 1956 reprint in Nature and Bryson outline [re] Kolin technique
  - Buchanan, Erskin and Mary (Mr. & Mrs.) [re] vacationing in Tobago, 1965-1970 (Box 2)
  - Burris, R.H., 1966 (Box 2)
  - Bursar, RU (Charles Petrzelka), 1960 (Box 2)
  - Burtner, O. [re] Kate (W.F. Goebel sister), 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Bussard, A., 1974 (Box 2)
  - Büttner, Werner, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - Butler, Patricia, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Cabot, George, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Camp Chester [re] sale of, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Charles [re] W.F. Goebel lectures, meetings attended, honors received for RI Press publication, 1958-1960 (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Robert A., 1967 (Box 2)
  - Campo, Anthony, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Canine College, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Carothers, Wallace H., 1934 (Box 2)
  - Carter, Herbert E., 1945 (Box 2)
  - Cecil, Hotel, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Chambers, Jack A., 1971 (Box 2)
  - Chanutin, Alfred [re] death of Marie (W.F. Goebel's sister), 1955 (Box 2)
  - Chauffage Moderne, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Cheers, (?) Date? (Box 2)
  - Cheever, F.S. [re] Goebel presentation at American Assoc of Immunologists meeting, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Childs, David, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Christensen, Halvar N., 1966 (Box 2)
  - Clarke, Talcott H. Mrs., 1956 (Box 2)
  - Closse, Annemarie, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Coburn, Alvin F., 1968 (Box 2)
  - Cole, Rufus [re] RU Review, September-October 1966, p. 19, Cole obituary, 1966 September-October; 3 pp carbon copy of typescript (Box 2)
    [See also Box 1, folder on Cole, Rufus.]
  - Coles, James Stacy, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Colvin, James C. [re] Goebel bio information for Illinois Alumni News, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Combs, Jerome T., 1964 (Box 2)
  - Commings, Elie de, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station [re] trees in Conn. home of Dr. Goebel, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Connecticut Light and Power Co., 1956 (Box 2)
  - Conner, Robert T. [re] RU air rights, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Converse, Allan Mrs., 1956 (Box 2)
  - Cook, Thos & Son, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Coolidge, John [re] disposition of Dr. Goebel's brother-in-law's mss to Fogg Museum, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Costen, M.M., 1954 (Box 2)
  - Cottrell, John [re] Robert E. Franzl, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Cotzias, George C., 1959-1974 (Box 2)
  - Craig, Lyman C., 1960 (Box 2)
  - [re] Crane, Ruth, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Crary, Miner D. [re] W.F. Goebel will, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Crawford and Levie [re] Julius, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Goebel, Jr. Estate (brother) - German books and pamphlets to Middlebury Collection (Box 2)
  - [re] Coulter, Elizabeth, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Cunard Steam Ship Co. Ltd., 1954 (Box 2)
  - Dale, Stephen Mrs., 1968 (Box 2)
  - Dalzell, Richard W., 1964 (Box 2)
  - Das, D.N., 1968 (Box 2)
  - Davies, D.A.L., 1956-1959 (Box 2)
  - Davies, Edward A., 1958 (Box 2)
  - Davies, Janet Mrs. [re] Mrs. Goebel contracting polio and aid from Nat'l Foundation, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Davis, Bernard D. [re] Proposals of election of Merrill W. Chase and Otto Westphal to NAS. Includes data, 1972-1974 (Box 2)
  - Davis, Deane C. [re] W.F. Goebel gifts to Middlebury College, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Dawes, A. Sidney, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Dean of Admissions for Women, Middlebury College [re] Helen Powell, 1963 (Box 2)
  - DeBruyn, P.P.H [re] Shuang S. Troy, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Dedonder, R.A. [re]. 1960 July 18-20 Gif-sur-Yvette, France. International Congress on the Biochemistry of Sugar (Box 2)
  - Dekker, Marcel, 1965 (Box 2)
  - deKriuf, Paul, 1941 (Box 2)
  - Delbruck, Max, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Delcambe, L., 1964 (Box 2)
  - Demenec, M., 1957-1958 (Box 3)
    Includes [re] John Hutton Jr.
  - Denman, T.H., 1963 (Box 3)
  - Densen, Peter, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Department of Game and Fisheries, Quebec, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Departure Passport (Selective Service), 1942 (Box 3)
  - DeWitt, Charles W., 1964 (Box 3)
  - Director of Operations, N.Y.C. (Box 3)
  - Department of Sanitation, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Dochez, A.R. [re] Goebel. RIMR staff appointments and promotions and Avery 1956 NAS Biographical Memoir by Dochez, 1941-1956 (Box 3)
  - Dole, Vincent P., 1960 (Box 3)
  - Dray, Sheldon [re] Earl Freimer, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Dryden, Hugh L. [re] Goebel 1958 election to NAS and Goebel and Amano ms at 1959 NAS annual meeting, 1958-1959 (Box 3)
  - Duane, Morris and Heckscher [re] Anne K. Goebel (daughter), 1955 (Box 3)
  - Duncan, Arthur [re] James Duncan, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Duncan, Leroy E., undated (Box 3)
  - Durrun, E.L., 1959-1961 (Box 3)
  - DuShane, Graham, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Dustman, John H. [re] Shuang S. Troy, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Eakle, Don, 1957 (Box 3)
  - Ebel, A. [re] Hans Weltzien, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Eddy, C. Manton, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Edelman, Gerald M. [re] E.S. Anderson in1968, 1963-1968 (Box 3)
  - Egami, L., 1964 (Box 3)
  - Ehrl, Rudy, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Eichwald, E.J., 1960 (Box 3)
    Includes proposed agenda for 1960 June NAS/NRC conference
  - Eiseman, Ben, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Elberg, Sanford S. [re] Guy T. Barry, 1957 (Box 3)
  - El-Din, Atef Gamal, Consul, United Arab Republic [re] Goebel's visit to Egypt, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Elliot, Roger, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Elliott, Elizabeth J., 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Elliott, Kathleen O. [re] Dr. Goebel's daughter attending Radcliffe, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Else, Margaretta, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Endeavour, 1959-1961 (Box 3)
  - Engel, Albert, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Enterprise Foundary Co. Ltd., 1962 (Box 3)
  - l'Espérance, Francis, 1972 (Box 3)
    Includes "Profile on Dr. Francis l'Espérance. Laser Luminary" MD, April 1972, p 101-102. (photocopy).
  - Esso Touring Service, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Evans, E.A., 1958 (Box 3)
  - Eylar, Edwin H., 1958 (Box 3)
  - Factory Mutual Liability Insurance Co. of America, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Farber, Saul [re] Gifts in memory of Cornelia Robb Goebel to New York Heart Assoc, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Farnsworth, E.A., 1957 (Box 3)
  - Farolfi, Mr. [re] Julius Goebel, 1957 (Box 3)
  - Fehrer, Elizabeth, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Fernandez-Duran [re] Anne Barkman (daughter), 1965 (Box 3)
  - Field, Henry, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Fieldston School, 1942 (Box 3)
  - Fischer, Herbert, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Fitch, Frank W., 1959 (Box 3)
  - Fitz-Hugh, Thomas Jr. [re] sister Marie, 1950-1951 (Box 3)
  - Fiyalka, A.J., 1966-1967 (Box 3)
  - Flanagan, Dennis, 1959-1960 (Box 3)
  - Flexner, Simon, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Fluevog, Thea, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Flinn, Waldo R., 1955-1974 (Box 3)
    Numerous handwritten letters by W.R. Flinn.
  - Fogelson, Suzanne, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Fogg Art Museum [re] Fiske Kimball, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Ford, Donald H. [re] Shuang-Tsao, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Ford, Helen Parker [re] Julius Goebel (father), 1948 (Box 3)
  - Fraillon, J.M.G., 1961 (Box 3)
  - Francis, Thomas Jr. [re] W.F. Goebel election to NAS, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Frank, B.L., 1957 (Box 3)
  - Franke, W.W. [re] Irwin Rüde, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Fredericq, Pierre [re] Colicines, 1952-1972 (Box 3)
  - Freeman, Stephen [re] gift to Middlebury College and Anne Goebel (daughter), 1957-1961 (Box 3)
  - Fremont-Smith, Frank [re] Goebel participation in 1956 and 1959 Conferences on Polysaccharides in Biology, 1955-1959 (Box 3)
  - French, Hollis, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Fritz, George, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Frost, Crawford, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Fujiwara, Michio, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Fuller, John L. [re] David Childs (Rufus Cole's grandson), 1959 (Box 3)
  - Gabrielian, Natalie, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Ganz, Aaron [re] Richard Reeves Garelik, Sanford D. [re] W.F. Goebel support of East River expansion by RU, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Garrison, Mortimer, Jr., 1960 (Box 3)
  - Gasser, Herbert S. [re] Guy Barry and Margeris Jesaitis in 1953, 1952-1953 (Box 3)
  - Gault, John A. [re] Dr. Goebel's experiences in the Hitler revolution in 1923, 1923-1957 (Box 3)
  - Gesellschaft für Immunologie, 1967-1969 (Box 3)
    Includes 1967 July booklet. "Statutes of the "Gesellschaft für Immunologie"
  - Gibbons, N.E., 1962 (Box 3)
  - Gilbert, Perry, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Gilbertson, Edna [re] Papers presented at 1959 April and 1961 Autumn NAS meetings, 1959-1961 (Box 3)
  - Gilman, Henry, 1955-1974 (Box 3)
  - Gim, Benjamin, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Gisler, Roland, 1966-1967 (Box 3)
  - Glanz, Georges, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Göbel, George 1964 [re] Genealogical research of Göbel family. Includes information by W.F. Goebel (Box 3)
  - Goebel, Anne (daughter), 1955-1959 (Box 3)
  - Goebel, Julius Jr. (brother), 1957-1969 (Box 3)
  - Goebel, Julius Mrs. (sister-in-law), 1968 (Box 3)
  - Goebel, W.F., 1960-1973 (Box 3)
    Includes 1973 W.F. Goebel ms "The Golden Era of Immunology at The Rockefeller Institute. Presentation on receipt of 1973 Avery-Landsteiner Prize. (17 pp photocopy of ms.)
  - Göing, Helmut, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Gold, Albert? [re] Forest Vey, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Goldstein, Irwin J., 1958 (Box 3)
  - Goldwasser, R.A. [re] 1964. March Israel Symposium on Molecular Aspects of Immunology, 1964-1965 (Box 3)
  - Goodgal, Sol H. [re] Rose Sapelli, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Goodman, Henry [re] Scientific American article on the colicines, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Goodman, Joel W., 1966 (Box 3)
  - Goor, Hyman [re] purchase of Pogo Cartoon books, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Goor, Ivan, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Gosselin, Lorraine, 1950-1952 (Box 3)
    Includes recommendations for
  - Gotschlich, Emil [re] typhoid vaccine for trip to Bangkok etc., 1967 (Box 3)
  - Gould, George [re] West Greenwich Mission of Christ Church contribution, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Grant, Diane, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Grassl, Edward F., 1962-1963 (Box 3)
  - Greeley, Paul Mrs. (Eunice), 1968-1972 (Box 3)
  - Greeley, Paul, 1957-1964 (Box 3)
  - Gressley, Gene M., 1972 (Box 3)
  - Griffin, F.J., 1969 (Box 3)
  - Griffis Faculty Club, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Grimm, Forrest C., 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Grossberg, Sidney E., 1961 (Box 3)
  - Grouse, Ruth, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Gustafson Emma R. [re] Elizabeth Miller Smidth, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Gyorgy, Paul [re] Primarily W.F. Goebel participation in 1955, 1956, 1959 Josiah Macy Jr. Foundation conferences on "Polysaccharides in Biology. ", 1954-1959 (Box 3)
  - Hugli, T.E. [re] Collaboration on "Colicin K" work. Includes Hugli lab data and publication, 1971-1973 (Box 3)
  - Hutton, John J. [re] "Colicine K" collaborative work and publications in PNAS 1961 and JGP 1962. Includes Hutton lab data and notes, 1959-1973 (Box 3)
  - Hadassah [re] Chloe Tal, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Haegle, Ursala [re] Avery-Landsteiner award, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Haff, Richard F., 1966 (Box 3)
  - Haggerty, James F. [re] Fritz Ørskov, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Haidemenakis, E.D., 1970 (Box 3)
  - Hale, Richard W. Jr. [re] Lac à Gravel Fishing Club, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Hall, Swan (Emmy) Mrs. [re] African Art lecture at RU, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Halmagyi, Dennis [re] Interview of; W.F. Goebel handwritten notes, undated (Box 3)
  - Halpern, Meyer, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Halvorson, H.O. [re] Ron Hinsdill, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Ham, Pok Sonn, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Hamamura, Norikatsu, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Hamilton, Frederick J., 1965 (Box 3)
  - Hamilton, Wm. R. Mrs, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Hamon, Yves, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Hanka, Ladislav J., 1958 (Box 3)
  - Harrison, J. Hartwell [re] daughter Cornelia, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
  - Harte, Robert A. [re] ASBC membership, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Hashimite Kingdom of Jordon, Embassy of, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Hastings, Bradford, Rector of Christ Church, Greenwich, Conn, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Haworth, W.N., 1936 (Box 3)
  - Health, Education and Welfare, Department of [re] W.F. Goebel's Medicare, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Hecht, Jacqueline T., 1973 (Box 3)
  - Heidelberger, Michael [re] Dr. Plescia, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Heinz, H.J. Co., 1958 (Box 3)
  - Helferich, Burchardt [In German], 1934 (Box 3)
  - Hensinki, Donald R., 1962-1965 (Box 3)
  - Henderson, Ernest III, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Herriott, Roger M. [re] "Festschrift" for John Northrop's 70th birthday and Goebel and Hutton ms as contribution to, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Hertz Rent A Car, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Hewitt, Edward R., 1934-1935 (Box 3)
  - Heydenreich, Ludwig H. [re] Fiske Kimball (brother-in-law), 1955-1958 (Box 3)
  - Hibbert, Harold [re] Mr. Babers, 1934 (Box 3)
  - Hibiscus Mofel [re] vacation in Key West, Fla, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Highman, Benjamin [re] Forrest C. Grim, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Hinsdill, Ron, 1962-1967 (Box 3)
  - Hirsch, James G. [re] 1961 Walter Morgan lectures at RU w corres from Morgan, J.L. Mosser and J.G. Hirsch handwritten note re 1973. Avery-Landsteiner Award and mss; Eve Briles, 1960-1974 (Box 3)
  - Hnis, C., 1957 (Box 4)
  - Hoagland, Charles L. [re] XIV polysaccharide samples by Goebel, 1939 (Box 4)
  - Hofsten, Bengt von, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Holland, Ann E., 1960 (Box 4)
  - Holland, I.B., 1972 (Box 4)
  - Holt, Henry & Co. [re] royalties for sale of Father's books, 1958-1974 (Box 4)
  - Homes, Jacques, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Homma, J.Y., 1965-1968 (Box 4)
  - Hoogerheide, J.C. [re] A.J. Kluyver, 1956-1966 (Box 4)
  - Horsfall, Frank L. [re] Rufus Cole and Dr. Horsfall's illness, 1957 1966 (Box 4)
  - Hosano, Gungi, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Hotchkiss, Robert [re] Siglinde (Dr. Goebel's dachshund), 1961 (Box 4)
  - [re] Hotchkiss, Rollin D., 1960 (Box 4)
  - Housewright, Riley D., 1957-1958 (Box 4)